etro.com 2017-06-18

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | Etro

**Information note and agreed services within the context of Legislative Decree No. 196 dated 30 June 2003 regarding data processing following purchases on the Etro website www.etro.com (il “Sito”)**

The purpose of this information note is to provide you with some information on privacy, as required by Article 13 of Legislative Degree No. 196 dated 30 June 2003 regarding the protection of the processing of personal data:

1.1. The data you provide are processed for the specific purpose of (i) taking action further to your requests to purchase Etro items, and (ii) complying with administrative, accounting and fiscal obligations connected with the sale of Etro items, and, in general, to comply with legal or contractual obligations that affect you.

1.2. The data you provide may also be processed, with your prior consent, for marketing purposes, e.g. to sign you up for our Newsletter, to send you advertising material and/or information brochures on products and services offered by Etro, via the post, courier, fax, email, text message, multimedia message or other remote communications methods. Your email address may be used for the purpose of direct sales of Etro products or services that are similar to those you have previously purchased. Finally, we may also contact you via social networks in order to share data, information and material about the World of Etro with you.

1.3. The data you provide, in connection with the date on which you made potential purchases and indications of the brands purchased, will also be processed, always with your prior consent, (i) to conduct market surveys, (ii) to know you better by using data analyses concerning your preferences in terms of purchased items and the identification of individual or group profiles, and to provide you with further personalised services in order to guarantee greater assistance that is tailored to your needs.

2\. Processing is undertaken using IT supports, electronic instruments and secure channels, and with prior implementation of suitable security measures, in compliance with the aforesaid standard. If you give your consent, your data will be used for processing, comparisons, selections, statistical reports or market research.

3\. The provision of data for the purposes outlined in point 1.1 is optional, but the possible refusal to provide required information that is classified as obligatory may make it impossible to process your request to purchase Etro items. If you purchase items online, during implementation of the contract, the request to cancel data required to carry out obligations resulting from the same contract, or the refusal to provide them, may make it impossible to continue the action. The provision of data for the purposes outlined in points 1.2 and 1.3 is optional and the possible refusal to provide your data for such purposes only makes it impossible to implement the actions described there.

4\. Personal data collected for the purposes indicated in point 1 may be shared with: banks, for the management of payments and transactions concerning online purchases, to third parties that support, depending on the case, the companies of the Etro Group or single boutiques in the management of transactions (such as couriers and haulers) if this is necessary in order to comply with contractual obligations that affect you, and to third parties providing email marketing services (for further information please consult the section Legal Area). The data you provide may also be used or shared, including abroad, for the purposes described above, even outside the European Union, to companies of the Etro Group or to Etro boutiques.

5\. The controllers for the processing of personal data are Etro S.p.A., Via Spartaco 3, 20135 Milano, Italy, and Arnaboldi S.r.l., Via Monte Napoleone 5, Milano, Italy (these two companies being defined collectively in this information note as the “Controllers”).

6.The Data Controller is Etro S.p.A., Via Spartaco 3, 20135, Milan, Italy, tel. Tel. +39 02 550201 Fax +39 02550208000; the employees entrusted with processing the data are all employees from time to time entrusted with the management of this website.

7\. All applications and requests regarding the processing of your personal data may be addressed to the Controllers or the aforementioned person in charge, at the following email address: [privacy@etro.com](mailto:privacy@etro.com).

8\. At any time you may exercise your rights in connection with the Controllers of processing, as provided for in Article 7 of Legislative Decree No. 196/2003, including the right to obtain confirmation of the existence or not of personal data about you, an indication of the origin of the data, and the purposes and methods of processing. You also have the right to request an update, modification or, if interested, integration, cancelation, anonymisation or blockage of data processed in violation of the law, including data that does not need to be stored within the scope for which the data were collected or later processed, including to resist, for legitimate reasons, the processing of your personal data, even though they are relevant within the scope of the collection, as well as the processing of personal data in order to send advertising material or direct sales material or to obtain marketing research or informational, promotional or commercial communications. Finally, you may refuse, now or during any possible future communication, to allow the use of your data for the direct sale of Etro items.

For more information on the processing of personal data by Etro via the Site, you may write to [privacy@etro.com](mailto:privacy@etro.com).

**Consent notice and service pursuant to Leg. Decree 196 of 30 June 2003, regarding data processing following registration on the website www.etro.com (il “Sito”) and for on-line purchases of Etro articles on the Etro website (il “Sito”)**

The purpose of this information note is to provide you with some information on privacy, as required by Article 13 of Legislative Degree No. 196 dated 30 June 2003 regarding the protection of the processing of personal data:

1.1. The data you provide are processed for the specific purpose of (i) taking action further to your requests to purchase Etro items, and (ii) complying with administrative, accounting and fiscal obligations connected with the sale of Etro items, and, in general, to comply with legal or contractual obligations that affect you.

1.2. The data you provide may also be processed, with your prior consent, for marketing purposes, e.g. to sign you up for our Newsletter, to send you advertising material and/or information brochures on products and services offered by Etro, via the post, courier, fax, email, text message, multimedia message or other remote communications methods. Your email address may be used for the purpose of direct sales of Etro products or services that are similar to those you have previously purchased. Finally, we may also contact you via social networks in order to share data, information and material about the World of Etro with you.

1.3. The data you provide, in connection with the date on which you made potential purchases and indications of the brands purchased, will also be processed, always with your prior consent, (i) to conduct market surveys, (ii) to know you better by using data analyses concerning your preferences in terms of purchased items and the identification of individual or group profiles, and to provide you with further personalised services in order to guarantee greater assistance that is tailored to your needs.

2\. Processing is undertaken using IT supports, electronic instruments and secure channels, and with prior implementation of suitable security measures, in compliance with the aforesaid standard. If you give your consent, your data will be used for processing, comparisons, selections, statistical reports or market research.

3\. The provision of data for the purposes outlined in point 1.1 is optional, but the possible refusal to provide required information that is classified as obligatory may make it impossible to process your request to purchase Etro items. If you purchase items online, during implementation of the contract, the request to cancel data required to carry out obligations resulting from the same contract, or the refusal to provide them, may make it impossible to continue the action. The provision of data for the purposes outlined in points 1.2 and 1.3 is optional and the possible refusal to provide your data for such purposes only makes it impossible to implement the actions described there.

4\. Personal data collected for the purposes indicated in point 1 may be shared with: banks, for the management of payments and transactions concerning online purchases, to third parties that support, depending on the case, the companies of the Etro Group or single boutiques in the management of transactions (such as couriers and haulers) if this is necessary in order to comply with contractual obligations that affect you, and to third parties providing email marketing services (for further information please consult the section Legal Area). The data you provide may also be used or shared, including abroad, for the purposes described above, even outside the European Union, to companies of the Etro Group or to Etro boutiques.

5\. The controllers for the processing of personal data are Etro S.p.A., Via Spartaco 3, 20135 Milano, Italy, and Arnaboldi S.r.l., Via Monte Napoleone 5, Milano, Italy (these two companies being defined collectively in this information note as the “Titolare”).

6\. The Data Controller is Etro S.p.A., Via Spartaco 3, 20135, Milan, Italy, tel. Tel. +39 02 550201 Fax +39 02550208000; the employees entrusted with processing the data are all employees from time to time entrusted with the management of this website.

7\. All applications and requests regarding the processing of your personal data may be addressed to the Controllers or the aforementioned person in charge, at the following email address: [privacy@etro.com](mailto:privacy@etro.com).

8\. At any time you may exercise your rights in connection with the Controllers of processing, as provided for in Article 7 of Legislative Decree No. 196/2003, including the right to obtain confirmation of the existence or not of personal data about you, an indication of the origin of the data, and the purposes and methods of processing. You also have the right to request an update, modification or, if interested, integration, cancelation, anonymisation or blockage of data processed in violation of the law, including data that does not need to be stored within the scope for which the data were collected or later processed, including to resist, for legitimate reasons, the processing of your personal data, even though they are relevant within the scope of the collection, as well as the processing of personal data in order to send advertising material or direct sales material or to obtain marketing research or informational, promotional or commercial communications. Finally, you may refuse, now or during any possible future communication, to allow the use of your data for the direct sale of Etro items.

For more information on the processing of personal data by Etro via the Site, you may write to [privacy@etro.com](mailto:privacy@etro.com).

The purpose of this Cookie Policy is to illustrate the types and categories of cookies, the purpose of cookies and how they are used by Etro S.p.A., Data Controller, with registered office in Milan, Via Spartaco, 3, and to provide useful information on how to delete or refuse cookies on the site. As Data Controller of personal data, Etro S.p.A. reserves the right to change this Policy at any time: any changes will take effect on the date of their publication on the Site.

What are cookies?  
Cookies are small text files sent by a server to the internet browser on the user's computer. They are automatically saved on your computer when you visit certain websites, and are automatically sent back to the server whenever necessary and on each subsequent visit. We use cookies for the etro.com website and its subdomains and request user consent where required by law or envisaged by applicable regulations to facilitate browsing and personalise information directed at the user. We also use similar systems to collect user data, such as IP address, type of browser and operating system and/or the web pages visited by a user, for statistical or security purposes. Cookies are useful as they allow our website to recognise the user's device and have various purposes, such as allowing efficient browsing between pages, remembering favourite pages and, basically improving the browsing experience. They also ensure that online advertising content is better suited to a user and his/her interests. If you decide to disable or refuse cookies, some parts of the etro.com website and its subdomains may not be accessible or may not function correctly. Therefore, for easy and full use of this site, you should configure your browser to accept these cookies. Therefore, for easy and full use of this site, you should configure your browser to accept these cookies. The etro.com website and its subdomains use the following cookies:  
Session cookies  
These cookies are essential for browsing the site and using site functionality. Without cookies, some functionality may not be available or may not function correctly. We use only those cookies that are strictly necessary to save an identifier allowing the user to be uniquely identified with respect to other users, in order to provide the user with a consistent and accurate service.

Performance cookie  
These cookies may be our own or from our partners, and may be session cookies or persistent cookies. Their use is limited to site performance and improvement. These cookies do not collect any data identifying the user. All of the data collected by these cookies is aggregated in anonymous form and used only to improve site functionality. Functional cookies These cookies are usually sent following a user action, but may also be used to provide a service that is not specifically requested, but offered, to the user. They may also be used to avoid offering a service to a user a second time. These cookies also allow the site to keep track of user choices. The data collected by these cookies is anonymous and cannot track user behaviour on other sites.

Third-party cookies for marketing/retargeting  
These cookies are used by partners of the etro.com website in order to propose our advertising messages when you visit other sites, displaying, for example, the most recent products you viewed on our site. These cookies may also be used to display products that may be of interest to you or that are similar to products you viewed in the past. These cookies do not entail any personal data processing, but may allow connection to the browser installed on your computer or other devices used during browsing..

How to disable cookies  
Personal data protection laws provide users with the option of disabling cookies already installed on their device ("opt out"). Opting out is permitted for "technical cookies" (Art. 122 of the Privacy Code) as well as for other types of cookies previously accepted by the user ("opt in"). By virtue of this distinction, users may disable and/or delete cookies ("opt out") using the browser settings by clicking on the relevant links:

Microsoft Internet Explorer https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/kb/278835/it

Google Chrome https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050?hl=it

Mozilla Firefox https://support.mozilla.org/it/kb/Eliminare%20i%20cookie

Safari https://support.apple.com/it-it/HT201265

Opera http://help.opera.com/Windows/12.10/it/cookies.html

Users may also disable and/or delete individual non-"technical" cookies installed by third parties via the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (EDAA) website at www.youronlinechoices.eu.

Technical/analytical cookies:

\- Technical cookies  
We use these cookies to guarantee efficient browsing, session stability, the contents of the shopping cart and login permanence for the entire session, as well as the country selected for browsing. We also use them to save user choices regarding the display of certain page elements, such as information and communication banners. Lastly, a cookie with duration not in excess of 12 months is installed to track user consent and prevent consent from being re-requested through the banners.

\- Analytical cookies  
Third parties use these cookies in aggregate and disaggregate form, to manage statistics. These cookies collect data on the use of our site to help us improve the user browsing and purchasing experience. All data is collected in anonymous form. For example, these cookies collect the following data: Third parties use these cookies in aggregate and disaggregate form, to manage statistics. These cookies collect data on the use of our site to help us improve the user browsing and purchasing experience. All data is collected in anonymous form. For example, these cookies collect the following data:Third parties use these cookies in aggregate and disaggregate form, to manage statistics. These cookies collect data on the use of our site to help us improve the user browsing and purchasing experience. All data is collected in anonymous form. For example, these cookies collect the following data:  
\- number of visitors, page views and browsing within the site;  
efficacy of purchasing campaigns based on the web traffic source;  
\- details on the products viewed and/or purchased;

Third-party cookies:  
• Google Analytics  
• Google Ads  
• Facebook  
• Twitter  
• Instagram  
• Pinterest
